<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Shern Shiou]]></title>
  <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-08-21T11:21:26+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[shernshiou]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life Updates]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/08/21/life-updates/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-21T11:20:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/08/21/life-updates</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Little bit updates since my last post. I am learning a lot lately, knowledge wise and spiritual wise. 
I think its important for a person to take a look at Maslow’s hierarchy of needs (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maslow's_hierarchy_of_needs">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maslow’s_hierarchy_of_needs</a>). It may or may not be applicable for each individual needs but I think every person have their own hierarchy of needs. Most importantly every needs are built entirely as an hierarchy where the lowest needs always Physiological. Each level of needs depends on their lower level of needs. If one’s fundamental needs cannot be achievable the top most needs collapse too. E.g. you cannot be successful at your work if you have trouble finding your food source and shelter (Physiological needs). On the other hand, life’s goal go hand in hand with your hierarchy of needs. In order to achieve higher goal, certain level of need need to be attain else the physical or mental properties of the person are not on par with the goal set. Take a look at your needs and set goal accordingly to achieve your needs and your future. </p>

<p>Recently I love a quote which I read from Siddhartha written by Herman Hesse. It says:-</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“Beautiful was this world, looking at it thus, without searching, thus simply, thus childlike. Beautiful were the moon and the stars, beautiful was the stream and the banks, the forest and the rocks, the goat and the gold-beetle, the flower and the butterfly. Beautiful and lovely it was, thus to walk through the world, thus childlike, thus awoken, thus open to what is near, thus without distrust. “ </p>
</blockquote>

<p>Yes the world is that beautiful, keep moving in tiny steps :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Youtube HTML Client using Backbone.js]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/04/04/youtube-html-client-using-backbone-dot-js/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-04T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/04/04/youtube-html-client-using-backbone-dot-js</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My first github project</p>

<p>Basically it fetch from youtube data api and populate using Backbone.js</p>

<p>Head over <a href="https://github.com/shernshiou/youtube-backbone">here</a> for the source. Fork and enjoy!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Religion and God]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/03/20/religion-and-god/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-20T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/03/20/religion-and-god</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I often was asked how Malaysian are you when you do not believe at a religion as the first Malaysian Constitution stated ‘Kepercayaan kepada Tuhan’ which roughly translate to ‘Believe in the God’. As a person that cannot understand religion, I do not subscribe to any of them. However throughout the years, from an atheist, slowly I begin to realise there have to be something larger than what we (human) can comprehend. In our daily life, there are mysteries we encountered. The mysteries that we cannot perceive yet it just comes so naturally. Therefore, I realised I need to recogize this element of unknown, element that is watching us everyday and element that is larger than us. Recognizing this element make me curious, make me small and feel belongs.</p>

<p>For me, religion is a medium. It serves well in the past as a part and parcel of human civilization. It teaches us the values and some knowledge when we have no foundation to rationalize. There are those dark ages in human civilization where we are ready to evolve into a larger societies yet values is the barrier. The best method at that time to inculcate the values and knowledge is through religion. Religion uses the power of unknown and fear (God) to strike knowledge to our heart. It serves us well until education and scientific methods teach us how to reason. I believe they has replaced religion to teach us the values and knowledge we need in this era. Who knows one day, some technology might replaced education and scientific method that can bring human to a higher level. But certainly, some parts of religion has obsolete by scientific method. The other havles of religion including moral and values that religion bring us is replaced by education.</p>

<p>I strongly believe there is no connection between the God and religion. Religions describe the God, the fanatics tries to be the along with the God and the spiritual leaders often used the God. In the end, I believe the God as a larger set of this universe, the unknown and the space. </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spoilt Apple]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/03/18/spoilt-apple/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-18T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/03/18/spoilt-apple</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Human resource is an important role for a company. Their job includes scrutinizing a candidate, hiring an employee or making sure the employee works with the company for the company. An employee can be compared to an apple. It is infectious as the bad bit will go viral affecting the remaining chunk. On the other hand, an employee with good attitude motivates the rest of the colleagues and teammates. It is essential for a leader to not only perform technically but also the attitude that creates positive force field.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robert Frost's Decision]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/02/27/robert-frosts-decision/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-27T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/02/27/robert-frosts-decision</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>During my secondary school, everyone in the school read a poem by Robert Frost called The Road Not Taken. It questions us to pick a path for your future. It teaches me on being responsible on the decisions. Its has been years after I first encountered this poem, this poem still does not fail to frequent me whenever I am making hard decisions. Dear Robert, did you really sigh when you took the road less taken? Just so you know, I do not think your sigh is a sign of regret. I guess its a human norm. In the end, human is just the greedy bunch. There is another thing I learnt so far. There is a greater power that is not up above but resides within yourself. When the moment comes, the moment that requires your decision, the answer will appear. It comes straight from your heart. No matter how much you wanna reject it, you just cant. Its instinct. Just follow your instinct, believe in yourself, be responsible, the world will be brighter.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wooooot!]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/02/23/wooooot/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-23T01:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2012/02/23/wooooot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just found out someone really did read my blog… Maybe I should post more.. :P</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Life]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/11/03/new-life/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-03T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/11/03/new-life</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a month into my new job, I got my new life.<br />
Despite the jam, I woke up early to get to my office.<br />
I learned to code, debug.<br />
The best part of the day when you get to type commit into version control.<br />
Back home, I cook my own dinner.<br />
Attend online lecture after that or continue on my journal paper.<br />
Before I sleep, I read a few chapters.<br />
I got to do what I like every seconds. </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[QString to Char*]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/10/13/qstring-to-char-star/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-13T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/10/13/qstring-to-char-star</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to <a href="http://developer.qt.nokia.com/faq/answer/how_can_i_convert_a_qstring_to_char_and_vice_versa">Qt Forum</a></p>

<p>Below help us to get Char* out from QString and the other way around:</p>

<div class="bogus-wrapper"><notextile><figure class="code"><figcaption><span>Convert QString to Char*</span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class="line-number">1</span>
<span class="line-number">2</span>
<span class="line-number">3</span>
</pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="c++"><span class="line"><span class="n">QString</span> <span class="n">inputString</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s">&quot;hello&quot;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="n">QByteArray</span> <span class="n">byteArray</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">inputString</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">toUtf8</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="k">const</span> <span class="kt">char</span><span class="o">*</span> <span class="n">cString</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">byteArray</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">constData</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>

<div class="bogus-wrapper"><notextile><figure class="code"><figcaption><span>Convert Char* to QString</span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class="line-number">1</span>
</pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="c++"><span class="line"><span class="n">QString</span> <span class="n">qString2</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">QString</span><span class="o">::</span><span class="n">fromUtf8</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">cString</span><span class="p">);</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I Became A Programmer?]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/07/21/how-i-became-a-programmer/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-21T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/07/21/how-i-became-a-programmer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I learnt programming even before I receive my former education in primary school. Even though I did not learn to create a full blown application, but it did teach me problem solving, flowchart and logic programming.</p>

<h3 id="the-turtle">The Turtle</h3>
<p>My first programming language is Logo (Wiki). Logo is console consist of a turtle that draws according to the command given. We can draw anything using command like Pen off, pen on, turn right, turn left… </p>

<h3 id="my-first-hello-world">My First “Hello World”</h3>
<div class="bogus-wrapper"><notextile><figure class="code"><figcaption><span>It drew a square box.</span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class="line-number">1</span>
<span class="line-number">2</span>
<span class="line-number">3</span>
<span class="line-number">4</span>
<span class="line-number">5</span>
<span class="line-number">6</span>
<span class="line-number">7</span>
<span class="line-number">8</span>
</pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="common-lisp"><span class="line"><span class="nv">FORWARD</span> <span class="mi">100</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="nv">LEFT</span> <span class="mi">90</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="nv">FORWARD</span> <span class="mi">100</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="nv">LEFT</span> <span class="mi">90</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="nv">FORWARD</span> <span class="mi">100</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="nv">LEFT</span> <span class="mi">90</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="nv">FORWARD</span> <span class="mi">100</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="nv">LEFT</span> <span class="mi">90</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Teka Teki]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/07/14/teka-teki/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-14T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/07/14/teka-teki</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="question">Question</h3>
<p>What does ps3 sets and women’s breasts have in common?</p>

<h3 id="answer">Answer</h3>
<p>Both are intended for children, but it’s the fathers that always end up playing with them.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Contributed by
M Bazli B Othman (ECRO/PETH)</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bersih Really Rally?]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/07/11/bersih-really-rally/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-11T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/07/11/bersih-really-rally</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last Saturday (9 July 2011), Malaysian all over the world came together and march to demand for cleaniness in Electoral. I was in Klang Valley but yet I didn’t join it. For me this march is even bigger than a march itself. Many would think it is a peaceful march for the better future for Malaysia. However, many people joined this rally with different purposes. Each have their own agenda to see them happen. I guess this rally may has strike in the middle how people from various corners want it.</p>

<h3 id="current-government">Current Government</h3>
<p>Since the beginning of this event (even from the proposal stage), the incumbent made a lot grey statements luring the BERSIH committee for the event to happen in a shape they wanted it. From banning the event, granting a venue yet retract it in the last minute, they are trying to test the limit of the people. Provoking the anger yet limiting the traffic into the city center confuses the people (organizer and the participants), all leads to their main objective. The signs and actions clearly show that they are striking fear to the rakyat to show their power. You never know, they might had planted someone inside the crowds to provoke them into hostility. At the end the peace rally became a non peace rally. With the police force using tear gas and chemical-laced water, the government made the whole scenario looks like angry-mob vs the police. This strikes two birds with one stones cause it also angers the business people around that area (quoting fake lost amount of economic lost). On top of that, using the mass-media the government are now able to paint the images of the opposition to cause the confusion to the non-intellectual people outskirt. All in all, the current government wanted to show their power and causes more people to hate the opposition to prepare for the upcoming election.</p>

<h3 id="the-opposition">The Opposition</h3>
<p>Some of you might be surprised, why are those old leaders from the opposition came to the rally knowingly they are unable to walk that far and get caught later? They too have their purposes. They are wise people. Having serving as oppositions for numbers of years, they knew in and out of Malaysian political scene. They believed a rally would not change anything in the end. The EC will be as kotor as long as the current government stayed. So why they came? First, they are borrowing this event as a free media to tear off the face of the incumbent. They uses BERSIH to tell the world how dirty is the election committee, how undemocratic is Malaysia. Knowing the leaders of the current government would not join this event (cause they have announced BERSIH as an illegal rally), they joined it to show how close they are with the rakyat hoping to get more trusts and loves from us which in the future they might get more votes. While walking with the rally, they hoped they get caught ‘live’ in front of the eyes. By getting caught, they showed how heroic they are by joining the people who get caught. On the other hand, it also shows that how brutal and unjust is our police force (under the provision of our current government). So you think they believe in clean electoral? NO, they came so they win.</p>

<h3 id="participants">Participants</h3>
<p>You guys are victims of the event of cat and rat. With or without BERSIH, do you realized that we are a victim of the dirty political scene between current government and the opposition? Joining the event and risking your life so that you can be a part of the change might be heroic. Therefore, this BERSIH 2.0 sighted more teenager than the previous rarely. Drawing blood from the nature of rebellious in the teenagers and social media, the organizers carefully crafted the whole package to suit them. What you did is risking yourself, made your parent worry and volunteer yourself as a tool for the both parties. As a tool in this event, I congratulate you guys because you have archived the effect intended for the both parties. As a cherry on top of the cake, you are recognized by the international bodies making them to focus on Malaysia for a day. Both the parties got they wanted but do you get the clean election you requested?</p>

<h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<p>The rally did not achieve the objective but only more economic lost (according to the news :P). To be BERSIH, we need to acknowledge the root cause. The root of our current situation is not how kotor is our EC or how bersih we wanted for our coming election. The root of all these are caused by how dirty are our politicians. BERSIH showed us how deep we had sank. We are so dirt cheap now. Both sides are using the rakyat to archive what they wanted. They do not only neglected our voice and right but also have the power to swing us however they wanted. At one side, they break and conquer us (PERKASA). On the other side, they played with our mind telling us how the current government is conducting the rasuah as if they did not. As a tool, the rebellions are blinded therefore they chose side. They forgot either place they stand, they still will land on a piece of shit or on a smelly dung. So why do you want BERSIH election but the political parties here came from the ass which are still KOTOR? Fix them first!</p>

<p>I wish I wish I can sit on a fence high enough to hold on a helping hand from the heaven sky.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pilihan Raya ke?]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/07/01/pilihan-raya-ke/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/07/01/pilihan-raya-ke</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="scenario">Scenario</h3>
<p>When they have their passport photo as their profile picture. (Be it Facebook, MSN….)</p>

<h3 id="answer">Answer</h3>
<p>lu ingat pilihan raya ke (You thought you are running for election?)</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Contributed by
Mr Ong XXX XXXN</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Installing Boost]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/06/23/installing-boost/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-23T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/06/23/installing-boost</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Simple command to install Boost for Ubuntu</p>

<div class="bogus-wrapper"><notextile><figure class="code"><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class="line-number">1</span>
</pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class=""><span class="line">sudo apt-get install libboost-dev libboost-doc</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Check Duplicate in MySQL]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/06/21/check-duplicate-in-mysql/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-21T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/06/21/check-duplicate-in-mysql</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Simple snippet:</p>

<div class="bogus-wrapper"><notextile><figure class="code"><figcaption><span>SQL to check duplicate entry</span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class="line-number">1</span>
<span class="line-number">2</span>
<span class="line-number">3</span>
<span class="line-number">4</span>
<span class="line-number">5</span>
</pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="sql"><span class="line"><span class="k">SELECT</span> <span class="o">`</span><span class="n">name</span><span class="o">`</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="k">COUNT</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="o">`</span><span class="n">name</span><span class="o">`</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="k">as</span> <span class="n">cnt</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="k">FROM</span> <span class="o">`</span><span class="n">members</span><span class="o">`</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="k">GROUP</span> <span class="k">BY</span> <span class="o">`</span><span class="n">name</span><span class="o">`</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="k">HAVING</span> <span class="n">cnt</span> <span class="o">&gt;</span> <span class="mi">1</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="k">ORDER</span> <span class="k">by</span> <span class="n">cnt</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Level of Desperation]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/06/08/level-of-desperation/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-08T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/06/08/level-of-desperation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Level 1: You miss that thing.</p>

<p>Level 2: You think of it everyday.</p>

<p>Level 3: You are finding something to replace it.</p>

<p>Level 4: You try to convince yourself that you have it.</p>

<p>Level 5: You hypnotized yourself that you are having it.. but your heart has given up.</p>

<p>Level 6: You already found a replacement for it.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>p/s: Sorry I do not have a Richter Scale for it.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Theory on Images]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/05/26/information-theory-on-images/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-26T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/05/26/information-theory-on-images</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the past, I have always encountered these questions while doing my research. To truly emulate human vision perception in computer vision, I need to understand how the mechanism works. These questions form the fundamental mechanism of human vision. Therefore, I decided to compute several images to proof my believe. My main hypothesis is human vision is represented in HSV colour model rather than RGB colour model. To proof this, I will be using basic Information Theory to compute the information composition in an single image both RGB and HSV.</p>

<h3 id="information-theory">Information Theory</h3>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">
\begin{equation} H(X) = -\sum_{x \in \mathcal{X}} p(x) \log_b p(x). \end{equation}
</script>

<h6 id="shannons-entropy-equation">Shannon’s Entropy Equation</h6>

<p>The basic Shannon Entropy will be used to compute each individual plane in an image. This entropy is used to measure the unpredictability. The easier to predict, the lower the entropy it has. In this case, I also made an assumption that entropy directly relate to the information contained / encoded within. If you need detail description on Shannon Entropy, head over to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Entropy_(information_theory)">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Entropy_(information_theory)</a> which contains fairly understandable explanation.</p>

<h3 id="methods">Methods</h3>
<p>A set of 20 various images from grayscale to single colour, from human and non-human images are collected. Entropy will be computed on grayscale mode, Red plane, Blue plane, Green plane as well as Hue plane, Saturation plane and Intensity.</p>

<h3 id="results-and-explanation">Results and Explanation</h3>
<p><img class="center" src="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//images/gallery/entropy_result.png" width="483" height="431" title="Result Table" />
As expected RGB plane has pretty similar entropy in every images. If one of the plane has low entropy, both the plane will follow including the grayscale version of the image. On the other hand, HSV has a pretty interesting results. Averagely, Intensity plane has higher entropy than the other Hue and Saturation. In the event of grayscale image (note Image 17 and 18), Intensity contain entropy but not the other two.</p>

<h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<ol>
  <li>Intensity planes contain more information. Therefore, we are able to perceive an image from only the intensity plane.</li>
  <li>Single colour image does has information but when converted to HSV plane, it represents 0 entropy in every plane.</li>
  <li>Human vision is closer to HSV than RGB. Notes: Cone cell in retina</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="references">References</h3>
<ol>
  <li>Wikipedia on Shannon Entropy <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Entropy_(information_theory)">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Entropy_(information_theory)</a></li>
  <li>Beginner explanation of how entropy is applied in classification <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1859554/what-is-entropy-and-information-gain">http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1859554/what-is-entropy-and-information-gain</a></li>
  <li>Kodak Lossless Image Suite used in Sample Images <a href="http://r0k.us/graphics/kodak/">http://r0k.us/graphics/kodak/</a></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS3 Gradient and Transparency]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/05/16/css3-gradient-and-transparency/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-16T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/05/16/css3-gradient-and-transparency</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Due to inconsistency of CSS3 implementation across different web browser, I wish to leave some note on Gradient and Transparency.</p>

<h4 id="transparency">Transparency</h4>
<div class="bogus-wrapper"><notextile><figure class="code"><figcaption><span>Mozilla and Webkit based</span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class="line-number">1</span>
</pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="css"><span class="line"><span class="nt">background</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="nt">rgba</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="nt">0</span><span class="o">,</span><span class="nt">0</span><span class="o">,</span><span class="nt">0</span><span class="o">,</span><span class="nt">0</span><span class="nc">.3</span><span class="o">);</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>
<div class="bogus-wrapper"><notextile><figure class="code"><figcaption><span>IE based</span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class="line-number">1</span>
<span class="line-number">2</span>
</pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="css"><span class="line"><span class="nt">background</span><span class="nd">:transparent</span><span class="o">;</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="nt">filter</span><span class="nd">:progid:DXImageTransform</span><span class="nc">.Microsoft.gradient</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="nt">startColorstr</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="nf">#50000000</span><span class="o">,</span><span class="nt">endColorstr</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="nf">#50000000</span><span class="o">);</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>

<h4 id="gradient">Gradient</h4>
<div class="bogus-wrapper"><notextile><figure class="code"><figcaption><span>Mozilla based</span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class="line-number">1</span>
</pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="css"><span class="line"><span class="nt">background</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="nt">-moz-linear-gradient</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="nt">rgba</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="nt">255</span><span class="o">,</span><span class="nt">131</span><span class="o">,</span><span class="nt">126</span><span class="o">,</span><span class="nt">1</span><span class="o">)</span> <span class="nt">0</span><span class="o">%,</span> <span class="o">(</span><span class="nt">255</span><span class="o">,</span><span class="nt">131</span><span class="o">,</span><span class="nt">126</span><span class="o">,</span><span class="nt">0</span><span class="o">)</span> <span class="nt">95</span><span class="o">%;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>
<div class="bogus-wrapper"><notextile><figure class="code"><figcaption><span>Webkit based</span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class="line-number">1</span>
<span class="line-number">2</span>
</pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="css"><span class="line"><span class="nt">background</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="nt">-webkit-gradient</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="nt">linear</span><span class="o">,</span> <span class="nt">left</span> <span class="nt">top</span><span class="o">,</span> <span class="nt">left</span> <span class="nt">bottom</span><span class="o">,</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="nt">from</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="nt">rgba</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="nt">255</span><span class="o">,</span><span class="nt">131</span><span class="o">,</span><span class="nt">126</span><span class="o">,</span><span class="nt">1</span><span class="o">)),</span><span class="nt">to</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="nt">rgba</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="nt">255</span><span class="o">,</span><span class="nt">131</span><span class="o">,</span><span class="nt">126</span><span class="o">,</span><span class="nt">0</span><span class="o">)));</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>
<div class="bogus-wrapper"><notextile><figure class="code"><figcaption><span>IE based</span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class="line-number">1</span>
<span class="line-number">2</span>
</pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="css"><span class="line"><span class="nt">background</span><span class="nd">:transparent</span><span class="o">;</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="nt">filter</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="nt">progid</span><span class="nd">:DXImageTransform</span><span class="nc">.Microsoft.gradient</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="nt">startColorstr</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="nf">#FFFF837E</span><span class="o">,</span> <span class="nt">endColorstr</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="nf">#00FF837E</span><span class="o">);</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>

<h3 id="references">References:</h3>
<ol>
  <li>MSDN <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms532930.aspx">http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms532930.aspx</a></li>
  <li>Stackoverflow <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/2293910/css3-transparency-gradient">http://stackoverflow.com/questions/2293910/css3-transparency-gradient</a></li>
  <li>CSS Tricks <a href="http://css-tricks.com/rgba-browser-support/">http://css-tricks.com/rgba-browser-support/</a></li>
</ol>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data Engineering]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/05/11/data-engineering/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-11T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/05/11/data-engineering</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since the invention of computing devices, we have seen numerous data explosions. Reasons? Storage devices are getting cheaper but the storage ability is growing. It is now easier to share information especially through the cloud. Connectivity between human and non-human became more robust and sophisticated. Devices are made widely available. But there is a big problem here. Although we have expected the growth of data exponentially, but there are little ways developed for us to manage and fully make used of the data available for the greater benefit.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5023/5693449522_57353dd78a_o.png" width="1086" height="769" title="Bin Laden death diaspora by SocialFlow" /></p>

<h6 id="bin-laden-death-diaspora-by-socialflow">Bin Laden Death Diaspora by SocialFlow</h6>

<h3 id="what-is-data-engineering">What is Data Engineering?</h3>
<p>We need people who are expert in managing the data. The experts may not be of computer science background because data engineering has been part of many profession. For example, statistician/mathematician often are good in explaining huge amount of data while neurologists have the knowledge on the data management inside our human brain. Their job scope should include more than choosing the right storage to preserve the data, system to organize the data, technology to retrieve the data. Data engineer need to churn out useful information from the data collection, explains the phenomenon and understand their nature. Data engineering will be the trend in the future while Computer Science will aid in providing tools to increase the performance of data engineer especially Machine Learning.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cuti-cuti Malaysia]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/05/09/cuti-cuti-malaysia/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-09T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/05/09/cuti-cuti-malaysia</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//images/gallery/redang.jpg" width="480" height="270" title="Pulau Redang" />
Can anyone identify where is this pretty beach?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crap Food]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/04/25/crap-food/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-25T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/04/25/crap-food</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//images/gallery/crap_food.jpg" width="640" height="480" title="Huge Crap Seafood Restaurent" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
