<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Thought | Shern Shiou]]></title>
  <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/categories/thought/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//"/>
  <updated>2012-08-21T01:04:10+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[shernshiou]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Life]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/11/03/new-life/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-03T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/11/03/new-life</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a month into my new job, I got my new life.<br />
Despite the jam, I woke up early to get to my office.<br />
I learned to code, debug.<br />
The best part of the day when you get to type commit into version control.<br />
Back home, I cook my own dinner.<br />
Attend online lecture after that or continue on my journal paper.<br />
Before I sleep, I read a few chapters.<br />
I got to do what I like every seconds. </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I Became A Programmer?]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/07/21/how-i-became-a-programmer/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-21T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/07/21/how-i-became-a-programmer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I learnt programming even before I receive my former education in primary school. Even though I did not learn to create a full blown application, but it did teach me problem solving, flowchart and logic programming.</p>

<h3 id="the-turtle">The Turtle</h3>
<p>My first programming language is Logo (Wiki). Logo is console consist of a turtle that draws according to the command given. We can draw anything using command like Pen off, pen on, turn right, turn left… </p>

<h3 id="my-first-hello-world">My First “Hello World”</h3>
<p><code>common-lisp It drew a square box.
FORWARD 100
LEFT 90
FORWARD 100
LEFT 90
FORWARD 100
LEFT 90
FORWARD 100
LEFT 90
</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bersih Really Rally?]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/07/11/bersih-really-rally/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-11T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/07/11/bersih-really-rally</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last Saturday (9 July 2011), Malaysian all over the world came together and march to demand for cleaniness in Electoral. I was in Klang Valley but yet I didn’t join it. For me this march is even bigger than a march itself. Many would think it is a peaceful march for the better future for Malaysia. However, many people joined this rally with different purposes. Each have their own agenda to see them happen. I guess this rally may has strike in the middle how people from various corners want it.</p>

<h3 id="current-government">Current Government</h3>
<p>Since the beginning of this event (even from the proposal stage), the incumbent made a lot grey statements luring the BERSIH committee for the event to happen in a shape they wanted it. From banning the event, granting a venue yet retract it in the last minute, they are trying to test the limit of the people. Provoking the anger yet limiting the traffic into the city center confuses the people (organizer and the participants), all leads to their main objective. The signs and actions clearly show that they are striking fear to the rakyat to show their power. You never know, they might had planted someone inside the crowds to provoke them into hostility. At the end the peace rally became a non peace rally. With the police force using tear gas and chemical-laced water, the government made the whole scenario looks like angry-mob vs the police. This strikes two birds with one stones cause it also angers the business people around that area (quoting fake lost amount of economic lost). On top of that, using the mass-media the government are now able to paint the images of the opposition to cause the confusion to the non-intellectual people outskirt. All in all, the current government wanted to show their power and causes more people to hate the opposition to prepare for the upcoming election.</p>

<h3 id="the-opposition">The Opposition</h3>
<p>Some of you might be surprised, why are those old leaders from the opposition came to the rally knowingly they are unable to walk that far and get caught later? They too have their purposes. They are wise people. Having serving as oppositions for numbers of years, they knew in and out of Malaysian political scene. They believed a rally would not change anything in the end. The EC will be as kotor as long as the current government stayed. So why they came? First, they are borrowing this event as a free media to tear off the face of the incumbent. They uses BERSIH to tell the world how dirty is the election committee, how undemocratic is Malaysia. Knowing the leaders of the current government would not join this event (cause they have announced BERSIH as an illegal rally), they joined it to show how close they are with the rakyat hoping to get more trusts and loves from us which in the future they might get more votes. While walking with the rally, they hoped they get caught ‘live’ in front of the eyes. By getting caught, they showed how heroic they are by joining the people who get caught. On the other hand, it also shows that how brutal and unjust is our police force (under the provision of our current government). So you think they believe in clean electoral? NO, they came so they win.</p>

<h3 id="participants">Participants</h3>
<p>You guys are victims of the event of cat and rat. With or without BERSIH, do you realized that we are a victim of the dirty political scene between current government and the opposition? Joining the event and risking your life so that you can be a part of the change might be heroic. Therefore, this BERSIH 2.0 sighted more teenager than the previous rarely. Drawing blood from the nature of rebellious in the teenagers and social media, the organizers carefully crafted the whole package to suit them. What you did is risking yourself, made your parent worry and volunteer yourself as a tool for the both parties. As a tool in this event, I congratulate you guys because you have archived the effect intended for the both parties. As a cherry on top of the cake, you are recognized by the international bodies making them to focus on Malaysia for a day. Both the parties got they wanted but do you get the clean election you requested?</p>

<h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<p>The rally did not achieve the objective but only more economic lost (according to the news :P). To be BERSIH, we need to acknowledge the root cause. The root of our current situation is not how kotor is our EC or how bersih we wanted for our coming election. The root of all these are caused by how dirty are our politicians. BERSIH showed us how deep we had sank. We are so dirt cheap now. Both sides are using the rakyat to archive what they wanted. They do not only neglected our voice and right but also have the power to swing us however they wanted. At one side, they break and conquer us (PERKASA). On the other side, they played with our mind telling us how the current government is conducting the rasuah as if they did not. As a tool, the rebellions are blinded therefore they chose side. They forgot either place they stand, they still will land on a piece of shit or on a smelly dung. So why do you want BERSIH election but the political parties here came from the ass which are still KOTOR? Fix them first!</p>

<p>I wish I wish I can sit on a fence high enough to hold on a helping hand from the heaven sky.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data Engineering]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/05/11/data-engineering/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-11T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/05/11/data-engineering</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since the invention of computing devices, we have seen numerous data explosions. Reasons? Storage devices are getting cheaper but the storage ability is growing. It is now easier to share information especially through the cloud. Connectivity between human and non-human became more robust and sophisticated. Devices are made widely available. But there is a big problem here. Although we have expected the growth of data exponentially, but there are little ways developed for us to manage and fully make used of the data available for the greater benefit.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5023/5693449522_57353dd78a_o.png" width="1086" height="769" title="Bin Laden death diaspora by SocialFlow" ></p>

<h6 id="bin-laden-death-diaspora-by-socialflow">Bin Laden Death Diaspora by SocialFlow</h6>

<h3 id="what-is-data-engineering">What is Data Engineering?</h3>
<p>We need people who are expert in managing the data. The experts may not be of computer science background because data engineering has been part of many profession. For example, statistician/mathematician often are good in explaining huge amount of data while neurologists have the knowledge on the data management inside our human brain. Their job scope should include more than choosing the right storage to preserve the data, system to organize the data, technology to retrieve the data. Data engineer need to churn out useful information from the data collection, explains the phenomenon and understand their nature. Data engineering will be the trend in the future while Computer Science will aid in providing tools to increase the performance of data engineer especially Machine Learning.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keeping yourself up to date]]></title>
    <link href="http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/04/20/keeping-yourself-up-to-date/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-20T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tranquil-bastion-2708.herokuapp.com//blog/2011/04/20/keeping-yourself-up-to-date</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I always believe you need to keep yourself abreast with new technologies if your day in and day out activities have to do with computer. You cannot runaway from learning new stuffs everyday if you would like to maintain your competitive in your field. This applies especially to those who majored in computing field be it Computer Science or Information Technology. Self learning is the no. 1 skill needed followed by Googl-ing. If you resist to change, you might be the next dinosaur waiting to be replaced.
Luckily, by taking advantage of the Internet, the people who work side by side with computers are able to keep themselves updated by using the tools online.
## Social Media
- Have a Twitter account and subscribe to tech news such as @mashable, @engadget …
- Official company Twitter like @microsoft, @google will twit about their product improvements and whats new.
Famous people like @kevinrose, @jeresig might provide insights on latest / future interesting tech
## News
- Use feedreader like Google Reader to subscribe to the latest tech news and blogs for upcoming news through feed like Gizmodo, BGR
- Join HN (http://news.ycombinator.com) where bleeding edge tech news are shared
- Sites like Reddit and Digg has some tech categories in it. Be sure to check it out.
- Newspaper (and any media linked to conventional newspaper agencies) are outdated can be completely waste of time.
## QA Knowledge Market
- Having doubts on something you barely know? Ask in Quora or Stackexchange. The people there are extremely helpful.
- Stackexchange has several different sites serving different needs. Go to Stackoverflow for more in-depth computing coverage.
## Podcast / Videocast
- Constantly checkout the podcast and videocast for new techniques (covering how to program..)
- Youtube and Vimeo serve a lot of video. Search and subscribe.
- TED.com is another source of interesting lecture on brilliant ideas.
## Honorable Mentions
- Facebook pages too serve some interesting information.
- For anything else, there is always our mighty Wikipedia.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Be sure to keep yourself up to date, what you did in campus is the past.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
