<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Life | Shern Shiou]]></title>
  <link href="http://shernshiou.github.com/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://shernshiou.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-10T21:24:48+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://shernshiou.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[shernshiou]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Porting to Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://shernshiou.github.com/blog/2012/08/21/porting-to-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-21T11:39:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://shernshiou.github.com/blog/2012/08/21/porting-to-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have slowed down my updates on my blog these months. Lately, I spend my time travelling so do my works. The other reason behind the reduced of new posts because I am considering alternative platform to Posterous. Some of you might know that Posterous is winding down after the acquisition by Twitter. After several trials, I’ve decided to settle with Octopress hosted with Heroku due to several reasons:-</p>

<ol>
  <li>Complete mirror of local copy</li>
  <li>Changes are tracked with Git</li>
  <li>Markdown</li>
  <li>Code snippet with Pygments (find some of them at <a href="/blog/categories/code/">Code Categories</a>)</li>
  <li>Awesome mobile theme</li>
</ol>

<p>But this platform has several downside compared to Posterous</p>

<ol>
  <li>Lack of other ways of posting (e.g. email, mobile)</li>
  <li>Hard to embed without writing some changes</li>
  <li>I’m not familiar with Ruby</li>
  <li>Size matters at Heroku (for free hosting)</li>
</ol>

<p>I’m at about 80% of the total progress because I am still finding ways to include more images (by including other hosting) and porting embedded IFrame. One custom changes I’ve made on this blog is the ability to display LaTeX Math Equation with Kramdown (thanks to <a href="http://greglus.com/blog/2011/11/29/integrate-MathJax-LaTeX-and-MathML-Markup-in-Octopress/">Greglus</a>). </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Population Growth]]></title>
    <link href="http://shernshiou.github.com/blog/2012/05/08/population-growth/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-08T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://shernshiou.github.com/blog/2012/05/08/population-growth</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Human must be the favourite creation from the Nature. We are not only blessed with the power to think and comprehend but also very much suitable for the current situation. Human population grows tremendously in recent centuries especially after World War II (refer to  <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Population_growth">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Population_growth</a>). Referring to the graph <a href="http://www.google.com/publicdata/explore?ds=d5bncppjof8f9_&amp;ctype=l&amp;strail=false&amp;bcs=d&amp;nselm=h&amp;met_y=sp_pop_totl&amp;scale_y=lin&amp;ind_y=false&amp;rdim=region&amp;ifdim=region&amp;tdim=true&amp;tstart=-304588800000&amp;tend=1304784000000&amp;hl=en_US&amp;dl=en&amp;ind=false&amp;q=world+data+population">here</a>, our population actually doubled from 1960s until now.</p>

<p>Once people thought we might experienced serious food crisis that will prevent the human to expand further however with the technology, we are able to produce food better for most of the people here (2 out of 7 billion people here still experiencing food security). </p>

<p>Can we keep populating the world more if we keep living longer, consuming the food and energy? There are signs we might hit the limit soon. With the growing competitiveness, some developed countries are experiencing lower birth rate. </p>

<p>I think we human are the greedy bunch. The mother earth has loved us so much, why are we keep taxing her? One day, the power of nature will strike us. :(</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robert Frost's Decision]]></title>
    <link href="http://shernshiou.github.com/blog/2012/02/27/robert-frosts-decision/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-27T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://shernshiou.github.com/blog/2012/02/27/robert-frosts-decision</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>During my secondary school, everyone in the school read a poem by Robert Frost called The Road Not Taken. It questions us to pick a path for your future. It teaches me on being responsible on the decisions. Its has been years after I first encountered this poem, this poem still does not fail to frequent me whenever I am making hard decisions. Dear Robert, did you really sigh when you took the road less taken? Just so you know, I do not think your sigh is a sign of regret. I guess its a human norm. In the end, human is just the greedy bunch. There is another thing I learnt so far. There is a greater power that is not up above but resides within yourself. When the moment comes, the moment that requires your decision, the answer will appear. It comes straight from your heart. No matter how much you wanna reject it, you just cant. Its instinct. Just follow your instinct, believe in yourself, be responsible, the world will be brighter.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wooooot!]]></title>
    <link href="http://shernshiou.github.com/blog/2012/02/23/wooooot/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-23T01:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://shernshiou.github.com/blog/2012/02/23/wooooot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just found out someone really did read my blog… Maybe I should post more.. :P</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Life]]></title>
    <link href="http://shernshiou.github.com/blog/2011/11/03/new-life/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-03T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://shernshiou.github.com/blog/2011/11/03/new-life</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a month into my new job, I got my new life.<br />
Despite the jam, I woke up early to get to my office.<br />
I learned to code, debug.<br />
The best part of the day when you get to type commit into version control.<br />
Back home, I cook my own dinner.<br />
Attend online lecture after that or continue on my journal paper.<br />
Before I sleep, I read a few chapters.<br />
I got to do what I like every seconds. </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
